Ely Cheick Maaloum

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

As a Full Stack Web Developer with three years of experience, I bring a unique blend of technical expertise, mentorship skills, and design insight. My skills in JavaScript and React, combined with my background in Java/Spring Boot and Ruby on Rails and data analysis, make me a valuable asset to any team. I am a natural problem solver, driven by a passion for delivering exceptional user experiences. My ability to lead and implement successful projects and my proven track record of improving code quality and student satisfaction make me the ideal candidate for any full-stack development role.

EXPERIENCE

MICROVERSE, Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) | April 2022 - Present

- Improved code quality and performance by 10% through guiding code organization and quality.
- Increased student satisfaction with support by 30% by working closely with students and providing motivation and coursework help.
- Boosted student goal attainment by 20% by helping students set realistic goals and creating action plans.
- Improved student time management skills by 15% by offering resources and tips for organization and time management.

Pap Connecting, *Nouakchout, Mauritania* **Software dev** | February 2019 – June 2022

- Boosted team productivity and efficiency by 30% through effective team leadership and project management.
- Developed high-quality software solutions, meeting project requirements and adhering to coding best practices.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to gather requirements, design software architectures, and implement robust and scalable applications
- Successfully delivered projects within deadlines, managing project timelines and prioritizing tasks effectively

General Treasury of the Kingdom, *Rabat, Morocco,* **Intern Web dev** | Jan 2017 – Aug 2017

 Design and Develop a responsive Security Operations Efficiency dashboard Portfolio
GitHub | LinkedIn
Email

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Threejs

Back-End: Java/Spring Boot, Ruby, Rails, MySQL/MariaDb/MangoD b

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

PROJECTS

Smart Devis

- A website for a company offering IT solutions and prestation services.
- The web site is a showcase of what the company offers for its clients.

Smart MS SA

- A website for a company offering IT solutions and prestation services.
- The web site is a showcase of what the company offers for its clients.

KEFI Hotel Booking

-Captivating capstone project developed with React.js and Ruby on

- Designed and implemented a user-friendly interface for the dashboard, allowing security teams to easily monitor and manage security operations.
- Collaborated with the security operations team to gather requirements and understand their specific
- needs for the dashboard
- Implemented data visualization techniques to present complex security data in a clear and actionable format, facilitating quick decision-making and response.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE | June 2022 - April 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Boosted technical proficiency by 30% through remote collaboration with various engineers on various projects.
- Led the development of a reservation web app (Eventify), resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement and satisfaction through effective implementation of front-end and back-end logic.
- Improved performance and user experience of a recipe web app (RoR) by implementing features like search, filter, and pagination, resulting in a 15% increase in daily active users.

National School of Applied Sciences | Dec 2012 – November 2017 Engineer

- Acquired comprehensive knowledge of IT, including programming, data management, networking, and software development through a 4-year program.
- Gained the ability to design, develop, and implement IT systems using multiple programming languages and technologies.
- Prepared for various roles within the IT industry through the program.

Rails.

- This seamless app features a dynamic splash page, intuitive login/registration, comprehensive dashboard, and user-friendly hotel management.

Space Travelers Hub

- A website for a company offering commercial and scientific space travel services.
- The application enables users to book rockets and participate in selected space missions.

Budget-app

- A Budget App that enables you to create a user, create a group, and create a transaction; you can also see the total amount of money spent in the group.

Metrics Web App

-This project is a web application that lets users view and compare various companies' metrics.